Amos Matthew

Frontend Software Engineer

(+234)9040178856	thiswayamos	@gmail.com	amosmatthew.vercel.app
https://www.linkedin.co	om/in/swayamos/	https://gi	thub.com/Swaymos/

SUMMARY

Frontend Software Engineer who develops modern, reactive, and user-friendly web applications using the latest technologies currently with 10 years of development experience. I believe a perfect blend of UI architecture is one, where the goals and needs are accounted for in an elegant, efficient, and robust design of the UI, building large-scale web applications, cross-browser platforms, and design constraints on the web, and building responsive user interfaces

EXPERIENCE

Amplafy Media July 2017 - June 2019

Frontend Developer

- Collaborated with the client to understand their specific requirements and customizations related to front-end technologies.
- Served as the technical point of contact (POC) and acting Tech Lead (Front-end) throughout the project.
- Utilized ReactJS, TypeScript, SCSS, Azure DevOps and KendoUl (Front-end Framework) to implement the client's desired front-end functionalities.
- Took responsibility for overseeing the technical aspects of the project, particularly focusing on frontend development.
- Worked closely with the development team to ensure the successful delivery of the client's requirements.
- Leveraged expertise in front-end technologies to provide insights, guidance, and support to the team
- Actively participated in decision-making processes related to front-end technology choices and implementation strategies.

Rillysoft Systems Feb 2014 - Dec 2015

Frontend Developer

 Received training in front-end technologies, specifically focusing on ReactJS, Tailwind CSS, and MaterialUI.

- Acquired knowledge and skills to write code that is scalable, maintainable, and adheres to industry standards
- Applied the learned concepts and principles to build multiple projects.
- Demonstrated proficiency in utilizing these front-end technologies to develop functional and visually appealing web applications.
- Emphasized the importance of writing clean and efficient code, ensuring that projects are of high quality and meet industry standards.
- Leveraged the features and capabilities of ReactJS to create responsive and user-friendly interfaces.

Frontend Developer

- The main objective of my role was to integrate a code the layout of the ticketing App enhancing its functionality and enabling secure online transactions.
- The integration aimed to provide users with a seamless and convenient payment experience, allowing them to make purchases directly within the web application.
- Collaborated with other Frontend and Backend Software Engineer to provide the best experience for lovers of the social and soft life.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Issue Forge Live O Code

React JS, Typescript, GraphQL, Ant Design, Refine, CodeGen, Vite

- Seamless onboarding with secure login and signup functionalities; robust password recovery ensures
 a smooth authentication experience.
- Full responsiveness across devices for consistent user experience; fluid design adapts seamlessly to various screen sizes, ensuring accessibility.

- Personalized user account settings for profile management; streamlined configuration options for a tailored application experience.
- Complete CRUD for company management and sales processes; detailed profiles with add/edit functions, associated contacts/leads, pagination, and field-specific search.

Social Sphere	• • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • • •	Live	Code
React JS, Typescript, AppWrite	, Shadcn, Tailwind Css		

- Implemented a user-friendly create post page with effortless file management, storage, and dragdrop feature.
- Implemented the React Query (Tanstack Query) data fetching library for, Auto caching to enhance performance, Parallel queries for efficient data retrieval, First-class Mutations, etc
- Enable users to like and save posts, with dedicated pages for managing liked and saved content
- Used Appwrite as a Backend as a Service solution for streamlined backend development, offering features like authentication, database, file storage, and more

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages:

JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML/CSS

Frameworks & Components:

ReactJS, Redux, NextJS, MaterialUI, TailwindCSS, SASS/SCSS, Bootstrap

Tools & Technologies:

VS Code, Visual Studio, Git, GitHub, Netlify, Vercel, Azure DevOps, Firebase

Developer Tools:

Jest, React Testing Library, Chrome Dev Tools

Design:

Figma, AdobeXD, Canva, Photoshop, Illustrator, Premier Pro, After Effects, Spline, Gimp

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology in Maths A	nd Statistics	
Seed Secondary School		2008 - 2014
Science Student		

2016 - 2022

INTERESTS & HOBBIES

Benue State University

- Anime
- Gaming
- Reading Technical Articles
- Reading Manga